Welcome back to Next Dev FM. My name is Ryan Vogel and I'm joined by my co-host here, Dan Gusswin.
And we've got a very special guest today, but before we get to that, Dan, I was pushing
some code on the Next Dev repository because we're trying to get that new UI update going.
And I saw something weird. It was actually the logo right here that kept popping up all over
my code review. Did you like rename your account like code rabbit or something like that?
Oh yeah, that's actually that really, really cool thing. It doesn't have anything to do with your
account. It's essentially an AI that reviews your code for you. And it has actually saved my ass
a few times before with the environment variables that I almost leaked. So you should really
listen to what this thing has to say. Oh wow. Well, that's really good. But I mean,
my open source repository, I mean, I'm not generating any money. So like, I don't want
it to be like super expensive or anything like that. How much is this going to cost me, man?
Well, uh, luckily for you, it is free on open source repository. So all you have to do is
just enable it. That's perfect. That's perfect. Thank you so much to code rabbit for sponsoring
all next dev lives. Check them out at dev link dot run forward slash code rabbit
and start doing PRs and code reviews just better. All right. We are going to bring forward our
guest, Matt Palmer. There we go. Let's get that all rearranged. Matt is a head of devro
or head of developer relations or shenanigans at replet. Matt, how you doing?
Doing super well. Great to be here. Thank you both for having me.
Awesome. Super excited to have you, Matt. I ran into you NSF at a party the other day. I'm like,
dude, you're so awesome. We must get you into Posca and now you're here was so quickly.
I'm just happy. But anyway, let's get to the juice support, which is who you are. What do
you do? Just give us a two minute intro so that people know who they're looking at.
Absolutely happy to. Yeah, thanks for the kind words there, Dan. I'm Matt, head of DevRel at
replet. Yeah, living in NSF, going to parties, doing the thing. Mission is to make coding,
make building with AI accessible to everybody. That's what I've been up to for the past
almost two years now. Yeah. And how did you get into developer relations?
Yeah, man. I feel like it was one of those things that kind of found me. I didn't really
in tech through data. So, started out first graduated school in finance, moved into data
analytics. That was probably the hardest thing. One of the harder things I've done in my life,
just kind of like saying, hey, I'm working in financial consulting. I want to be doing SQL in
Python. And I'm just going to teach myself how to do those things. So, you know, I bought
a giant Python textbook, taught myself SQL, and it just applied to like a ton of jobs. Shout out
to like my first manager, Brent, who like totally took a chance on me and said, hey, we're going
to bring this guy who doesn't really know what he's doing, kind of learned how to be a data analyst,
who was a data analyst at all trails. As a matter of fact, that's kind of a throwback, but
got into data engineering just because I loved the technical side of things. But I think after
a certain point, I realized, okay, I can't sit in, you know, a dark room and just write code.
I want to tell people about these things. So, I started writing like these really bad,
these really shitty blog posts on like, what an OLAP database was, what an OLTP database was. And
at some point, somebody was like reading these blog articles at O'Reilly, and they reached out like,
oh, hey, we want you to write a white paper with Databricks. We want you to write a white paper
with this company called Colas. Again, huge shout outs to these companies who are like, oh,
yeah, here's this guy. He's just like writing about data stuff, you know, we'll take a bet
on him. And those opportunities kind of led to some courses, did a course with LinkedIn on
data transformation, led to some other opportunities. And again, this whole time, I was a data engineer
just going to conferences and sharing my thoughts. And I think I realized, hey, I want to do this
full time. Like, what is this called? And it was the same thing when I got into data analytics.
I didn't even know what data analytics was. I was just like, hey, I want to do this. I want to
write Python, I want to write SQL, I want to write scripts. What do you call people who do
those things for their career? And so very similarly, you know, I was like, what do you
call somebody who's an engineer, but then like, tells people about how things work,
or helps educate people or explains things. And some people call it DevRel. So, you know,
I got a job in San Jose, actually, probably three years ago, doing DevRel for a data engineering
company. And, you know, I was working remote through the pandemic, through all this stuff,
and I was really wanting to make a bet on in person work, sold everything I owned,
I was living in North Carolina at the time, everything I owned fit in my truck,
drove across the country, like camped along, it was actually a blast, just left everything behind,
drove out to San Jose, did that whole thing, found Replet. And then I was like, hey, you know,
I guess I'm gonna teach people with vibe code. Well, actually, at the time, Replet was about
deployments and about writing code. And I thought, oh, wow, this would be an amazing opportunity to
be able to teach people how to use like this deployment stuff, which was really painful at
the time, right? If you remember a few years back, like I remember when I got into data
analytics and data engineering, the thing that was hardest for me to learn was DevOps, I was like,
okay, I can write Python scripts, I can write stuff that work can work. At the time, I was like
writing streamlet apps. I didn't know like how to deploy it or what to do with any of these things.
And so, you know, I joined Replet with the intention of making that easy and educating
on those topics. But, you know, Sonic came along, AI came along, and now I'm teaching
vibe coding. So that's kind of been the journey soup to nuts. But you know, it's been really
great. Wow, it's actually an incredible journey from valuation spreadsheets to developer relations.
I don't think I've ever heard anything like that. Yeah, exactly. You know, I it's, it's crazy,
I think about four or five years ago, what I was doing. It's like, you know, like you said,
valuations, I was doing debt valuation for commercial real estate companies, you can actually
like value the debt that a company has, if you're like JP Morgan or Blackstone or something,
like you take out a bunch of loans to finance buying real estate. The loan exists on your
balance sheet. And based on where interest rates are, that loan has some value. So like,
it could be worth less than the actual amount of debt. But from that, I was like living in
Pennsylvania as like this whole thing. And now I'm like, I live in SF, I get to make apps for
fun and talk to you guys. So yeah, completely crazy stuff, man. Yeah, yeah, that's super cool.
And it's, it's interesting, because I've definitely seen like the evolution of Replet over the years.
Because about I think it was about three years ago, I only knew Replet as like this platform that I
would write like C++ and like Python on for like my school classes. And it was just this platform
that we use to kind of like run and execute this code. And then that's about it. And now it's kind
of reshaped into this sort of not necessarily a vibe coding, but like a vibe infrastructure type
thing where it handles everything. And you can just sort of use AI to interconnect everything
like that. But obviously, since you've had your sort of foundations and everything like that in
data, how do you see that sort of incorporate in your day to day? Because I'm sure some of those
habits probably are still there about understanding data, conceptualizing it and working with it.
Does that like a does that kind of get into your day to day a little bit?
Absolutely. I mean, in my opinion, everything is data, right? I'm biased. But you know,
like, if I'm building an app, or if I'm teaching people about, you know, building vibe coding
applications and whatnot, it's like, understanding data structures is actually a huge advantage,
right? And more than that, just the primitives, what is a database, you know, like, what is a
table? What is a column? How do you think about things in a data oriented way? If I'm starting to
build an app, like I like fitness, I'm working on some like fitness stuff on the side. I'm
probably I'm breaking these ideas down into primitives and thinking them at the thinking
about them at the table level and how they relate to one another. So I'm like, okay,
well, like maybe I have a program, the program is made up of weeks and days and sets and reps.
And like, you can architect the data model for that application. And then the logic for
the application almost just follows from the data. It's like, oh, well, once I decide on
what the data model looks like, everything else just kind of falls into place, like the logic
for what I'm building. And so like, data can really be foundational to any type of application.
Does that mean you need to be a data analyst or data engineer to do this? No. But if you're new to
building, if you're a new coder, if you're someone who's trying to learn, data can be a really great
place to start. And understanding how some of these systems work can be really advantageous.
So I see it a lot on the educational piece and on the like building piece. But then, you know,
like, reading a lot of code with AI these days, and just understanding like what object oriented
Python is or having the background and, you know, like kind of data and pro data engineering
is useful every day. So hopefully that answers your question.
No, yeah, definitely does. Yeah, it's it's, it's interesting, because especially now with AI
conversations, tool calls, everything like that, that's all just data. And then that data needs
to be reformatted into the AI and everything like that. And I was watching something the other day,
where this company is essentially paying like real coders and real programmers to work on
these fake projects that will never get shipped to have high quality production level code.
And they're just selling that to essentially AI data companies and everything like that.
And it's like, we're not even doing it for the love of the game now, we're just doing it for
the love of the data. So it's, it's really interesting how, how crazy data centric the
world is right now, because we're running out of data with all these AI agents and everything.
Well, there's no such thing as running out of data. There's running out of high quality data.
That's exactly right. If you I think, study last year, disclose some to like,
hundreds of zettabytes stored worldwide. Can you imagine how big of a number it is? I'm not even
sure. I know how many zeros that is, but it's a lot. Yeah, there's a lot of data to deal with.
But curious, going back to our questions, that you mentioned that you wanted to teach people,
like, that's something that people don't know about themselves. And I've discovered that
randomly in their lives. I'm curious, at what point did you realize that you enjoy teaching people
things? That's a great question. Okay, so I'm gonna answer this first. I'm gonna say,
I just think about like data, I have this amazing, maybe the best piece of company merch
that's ever been given to me by I think was thought spot at a snowflake conference.
They gave me a hat, and it says Data Daddy on it. That's all it says. And if I'd known we were going
to go down this rabbit hole, I would have brought on this podcast, but probably best
merch of all time. I blacked out the spot logo. So just it's just a hat that says Data Daddy.
And I haven't broken it out in a bit. So next SF party I go to, I might be wearing that hat.
But back to your point. How did I know I want to educate? I don't think I ever like,
I don't know, maybe it's not traditional education, especially like online, it's very one way.
So you create something, you don't necessarily know who engages with it. Or maybe some months later,
you hear from someone, oh, this video really helped me. This blog really helped me. I really
enjoyed this piece you wrote, or read a book, and I like never know really who read it or who got
value from it. But I think the thing for me was, I was so enamored with learning, like,
oh, I built this project, and it had this technology in it. Like I learned about this
thing, replant, and I had all these problems that I couldn't figure out with deploying
things before. But today, I was able to deploy something really fast. Everyone should know about
this. Like, everyone needs to know that this is the best way to do this thing. And I get enamored
with doing things efficiently, or technology just gets me so excited that it's like, I feel
it's like my job to go and be like, hey, you guys are doing stuff the wrong way, you could
be doing it better, there's a better way of doing things. And I learned about this,
and I'm so excited and so passionate about it, I want to share it with you. And something was
through that, that process of like discovery, understanding and sharing, just basically like
my own learning, they got me really motivated and really excited to say, I want to go teach people
about these things, not because inherently, like I enjoy necessarily like the process of teaching,
but because I think it's the most important thing and the most exciting thing that everyone knows
the best way of doing things. And they're these exciting technologies that exist.
As an ending, it's almost like it's your natural calling that you've found, I must show others what
they can do with technology of today. Sure, sure. But it starts, it starts with building,
right? It starts with like, what am I going to do? You know, if I have a free morning or free
afternoon? Well, I'm probably like hiking or something, you know, I'm like, I also love a
lot of other things. But one of the things is like, I want to just like build cool stuff,
right? I want to try and make things more efficient. I want to create something creative,
I want to create something for people to engage with. And then through that process,
that creative process, you like learn about these all these interesting things. And it's
just like this endless rabbit hole. It's really fun to go down.
Yeah, and I think that's like a crucial part of like, well, I've seen with like other dev rel
people, it's like they don't create content because they have to, they create it because
they love it. And that's I vibe with that very, very much so, where it's like all of my little
side projects and stuff like that. I make videos and talk about how that happened and stuff like
that, because I find it fun. I find it exciting and engaging. And like just today, for example,
with inbound, there was an outage due to like some SES configuration error. And I feel like a
normal company or something like that, or a normal person would just kind of fix it and then call
it good or whatnot. But I was like, I looked into it. And then I kind of wrote like a like
a video blog post about it and posted that I'm like, here's what I learned. And here's what
you can learn as well. And I feel like all of us dev rel just kind of get that. And we're like,
I learned this. And I feel like I should compact this and present this to you. So that way you
can learn it as well. Yeah, absolutely love that. Yeah. So leading into that, if a data engineer
asks, how do I break into dev rel without starting from like absolute zero, what would you like
kind of recommend them to do? Because there's like a bunch of different ways that you could
kind of do this and be like, just go grab a Lumix s five to camera and start filming or
something like that. What would kind of be your workflow be like for that?
Yeah, I would say, you know, go buy the most expensive camera you can go get your red
AK, spend two years learning how to edit video. These are the things not to do. And my advice
actually would be exactly the same for any profession. If you said how do I become an AI
engineer? How do I become a data analyst? How do I become a data engineer? Just start doing it.
Like you don't, there is no magical path. There is no, there's no like special road,
especially in tech, right? Okay, maybe if you want to be a doctor, there is a very
thought out path to becoming a doctor that you just kind of have to do. And that's like
how the world works. We need more doctors. But in tech, you just manifest whatever you
want to do, or at least that's how I look at it. Now, there are a bunch of different
ways that you can approach that maybe you find a mentor, maybe you get involved in some
communities, you start going into like a discord group, you know, it's like you you insert
yourself into a collection of people that they're already doing these things. And you kind of like
through osmosis become engaged in that activity. I think that's really important. But the most
straightforward one is you just open up your laptop and you say, Hey, you know what, I want
to build something and I'm gonna share it with people. And it's kind of a long road, right? Like
it's it can be kind of a lonely road. But I think that part of it is finding people that love to do
what you love to do. And so, you know, I'm a huge advocate of seeking out where the people who are
the best at what they do are and going there physically. That's why I live in San Francisco.
I think maybe Dan came here for similar reasons. And I see that as kind of like a shortcut or a
superpower of like, hey, I'm gonna go, we go find these people, I'm gonna go engage with this
thing. And then I'm also just gonna do it on my own, right? And I'm gonna ship it. And so like,
you know, my advice is always like, build something cool, open up your laptop and tell people about
it. If you want to write, if you want to create video, if you want to, I don't know, go talk about
it in person face to face. That's all that's DevRel. Through that you meet people, you do stuff,
and it just happens, right? Yeah. And I wanted to pull up a post that you shared on Twitter
about your setup, what you're using for producing content, I found that very inspiring,
especially the part on the image from the top left, the quick disclaimer, like, just go and start
right now. Yes, you with your MacBook, camera and mic, I found this super, super awesome, like,
it's literally all you need to do just start, just do the thing. And people always get that wrong.
Yeah, I get this question all the time. And it might be tough to see on the screen here,
if you're on a smaller screen. But like, if you click on that image, yeah, on the top left,
because people ask this question. The first thing I always tell them is, this isn't even
really Yeah, here you go. You can kind of see it. The disclaimer is, you know, you shouldn't
feel like you have to spend $5,000 to make great content start right now. Yes, you with your
MacBook, camera and mic, because that's what I did. And, you know, people are always like,
Oh, tell me about the boom mic that you use. Tell me about camera that you use. But like,
unless you're consistently producing and creating, that might not be the right question to ask.
All that stuff comes later. And with my own content, like, if you look at the videos,
maybe a year and a half ago, they were like very bad, or even two years ago, it was very bad.
But I recorded courses in my first dev rel job with my MacBook camera and my and my AirPods.
And we shipped them and people got value from them. And look, there are a lot of people that have
a lot more followers and a lot more success than I do that have a shittier setup than I do.
And they're doing just fine, right? So like, all of the nice stuff is just,
you know, flourish. And I think, don't get me wrong, it's part of being a professional that
you care about the way that your content looks and sounds and the way that you present. I think
that's all very important. But the content is more important than the fidelity in some regards.
So like, you can always become a better speaker, become a better presenter without the equipment.
And that's kind of what I tell people. Yeah, absolutely. Your most valuable piece of equipment
is yourself and your tongue, right? Like, moving it and making things sound nice.
I think maybe it was, I can't remember who it said, maybe Tiago Forte, somebody else online,
protect the asset and the asset is up here. So everything that you should do is
revolves around protecting the asset and making yourself a better person and a bill,
like more able to produce higher quality work or accomplish whatever you want.
Yeah, that's right. Anyway, getting back to you and your developer relations journey at Replit,
when you joined the company, they weren't exactly what they are today, as you mentioned,
I'm really curious, what did you walk into when you joined Replit at first? What was going on?
Man, a lot of things are going on. So I mean, first thing I have to say is like, big shout out to
David Hong, DH, he hired me at Replit. Again, you know, taking a bet on somebody that I've been
doing dev rel for a few years at the time. Coming from data engineering, it wasn't like,
you know, Replit was like the perfect fit. And I know there were a lot of other people
that were interested in the opportunity. But I joined and Replit, as I mentioned,
was just a tool for deploying code. As Ryan mentioned, you can run C+, you can do, you know,
Python, JavaScript, Rust, .NET, whatever you want. One of the things that makes the platform amazing
is that you can run a bunch of different stuff on it. But it was a place for technical people
that was more simpler than using other CLI-based tools for deployment or other more complicated
DevOps tools to write code in the browser without installing anything and deploy it quickly.
So when I joined, I thought, oh, cool, I'm going to teach people this simplified process,
it's all going to be about writing code and creation free GBT 3.5. The company, what I didn't
know was kind of in the midst or on the cusp of undergoing a major reorg. So a few months after I
joined, this is all kind of public information you can read about it, there was like a very big
layoff impacted, you know, 30 or 40% of the company. So we went from being, you know, like
140, 130, 140, when I joined, down to being under 100. I was the only person left on
the marketing team after that layoff. And the summer of 2024, summer into fall,
it was like a really tough time, because you know, like you undergo a layoff, everybody's
morale is pretty low. You know, we were, the replica has always been an amazing product and
a product for builders. But like commercially, the success wasn't necessarily there. And so
there's this very painful pivot that had to take place over the course of a few months. And so
I think from, you know, when I joined, which is like 130, it went all the way down to like
50 or 60. Again, that's, that's like a really painful process. And in that summer, I was just
kind of like, trying to do my best, you know, again, we didn't really have a marketing team,
I was creating content, I was pushing videos also became known as kind of like the video guy,
some sense. So like, if you look at the original agent launch video, it was just like,
me with my camera and a tripod recording Amjad, doing the demo on his laptop, and I like edited
it. I remember there's a photo on Twitter, somewhere like me, in like the quote unquote
war room with the AI team, like shipping the original agent at like 2am. You know,
like I'm editing the launch video. It's absolutely ridiculous stuff. But yeah, this is there's this
like long, painful process. And then this big bet that obviously Amjad and Michaela and the
company leadership made on AI and on ruplet agent, that then paid off and turned us into kind of
this vibe coding company or what we were. But like the the journey to that was very,
very challenging, right. And a lot of a lot of really great people I worked with,
who are no longer at the company, it's still obviously amazing people we keep in touch,
a lot of people at the company that stuck that out that kind of like fought through
that really challenging time. And so yeah, that transition from
ruplet, as everyone knew it a couple years ago to ruplet agent, ruplet vibe coding company,
was a painful one. But one that you know, will require a lot of hard work, a lot of really
amazing people that I'm grateful to work with every day. Yeah, that's Yeah, I can definitely
see the evolution of that and the evolution of quality as well, which leads me into our next
question. So we have Lee Rob on here a couple weeks ago. And he said the most important
indicator for like KPIs and tracking and stuff like that is quality. How well does your quality
evolve over time? So what do you sort of you because every devil kind of has a different way
of like their KPIs and measurements of success? How do you and your team sort of justify and
like, I don't know, measure that stuff. I think quality is a good one. It's a bit of
it. I think everybody has their way of measuring these things. And again, like I said, if you look
at my first videos, they're terrible, if you look at my videos, now, they're better. I still
see places where they can improve. And I hope in three years, right, I look at it, I say they're
the best, right. So definitely, I want quality to the quality of the content that I create,
the quality of my writing has improved a lot as well. But like, how do I how do I measure that,
right? The perhaps a lagging indicator of quality is
engagement. That's not always true. It's imperfect metric,
right? You can have content with very poor quality that gets
high engagement. But if you think about it kind of like a
funnel, and this is this is how I think about it, right? Think
about the product funnel, you have, you know, maybe some
awareness, are people aware of your product engagement? Are
people engaging using the product? Down the funnel, you
have something like adoption? Are they like actually using it
day to day? Power users, champions, purchasers, right?
Like, this varies by the product. I think to typically
develop relations, works somewhere in the middle of that
funnel. Engagement adoption. And that's where like, if you read
Swix's blog posts, measuring dev rel, it's kind of like monthly
active users, it's kind of like the gold star. How do you
measure that, right? That's challenging. Maybe you put UTM
parameters on your links, you use a tool like amplitude or
post hog to say how many users are engaging with these UTM
params, how many are entering the product through my means. But
for many of us, we're not working for consumer products.
We're working for developer tools. I'm grateful at Replit
that we do have massive volume. And I can move some of these
numbers in a tangible way. But you know, for many of us, it
might be a little bit different. Hey, maybe, you know, the
bigger metric that we're moving here is like enterprise
leads. Is there a way that we can measure the number of users
from enterprise that are engaging with our content. And
you know, to to Lee Rob's point, I think in some sense, these
metrics follow from quality. So if I'm continuously pushing the
quality, are people getting value out of the thing that I'm
delivering? That's actually what these numbers are
measuring. The number of active users that I'm driving are
directly correlated to the value that I'm providing with
the content that I create. And that's highly correlated with
the quality of the content that I'm creating. And so yeah, as
I think about metrics, the goal should always be to benefit the
user in everything that you do in product endeavor, right in
marketing, you're talking about marketing, marketing is kind of
a dirty word. But really marketing is just, hey, I
didn't know about this thing. And now I know that it can
help me. And so like, yeah, that's actually benefiting me
like good marketing is helping people. Um, but I think about
all through the lens of like, how do we help the user and
provide as much value as possible? And then what are some
ways that we can measure that, you know, like I don't,
it's a little superficial, but like the number of followers
that you have the number of people that engage with your
content in an ideal world is a reflection of if you're doing
the right thing. So, you know, take it for what it's worth. I
think it's different at every company. But typically, I look
at DevRel like a funnel. And then we pick some parts in the
funnel, maybe typically middle to bottom, depending on the
goals of your company, and then measure those things,
right? How many people are engaging? Are we able to
drive that? How many people are converting or becoming
champions? Typically, that tends with towards more
community, things towards the top of the funnel are a bit
more advocacy slash marketing. And then the middle of the
funnel is developer relations or experience.
Yeah, very, very good take. And I don't think it's all
that important to be stuck up on the numbers. Because at
the end of the day, the journeys that developer
relations referred customers usually go through are so
long, or so like exotic that it's literally impossible to
quantify. So yeah,
actually, and I have another comment on that, since you
brought it up, I was speaking with another DevRel. And, you
know, one thing he said is, hey, it's actually, especially
at a startup, it's a lot about trust, because there aren't
super concrete metrics in a lot of cases. And so, if you're
bringing on a DevRel, if you're a DevRel, and you're
hiring, you have to be hiring for people that you trust
that even if I'm not, you know, there's not somebody
breathing down your throat with like some like quarterly
metric for you to hit, you're going to go out and do
the right thing. You know, a lot of it is just like, if
you're at a startup, I don't know that everybody that's
watching this has worked at a startup, things are fuzzy,
and things are gray, and things are not, you know, like
big public company, like metrics, like, you know, just
kind of Amazon, you're just like cranking through wrote
writing code, and you have to make decisions. I have to
say, what's the best for our users? What do I see?
What am I going to invest my time in this week? And
so, yeah, there's like a big element of trust there
before you get to the metrics. And don't get me
wrong, metrics are super important, because a lot of
times, you know, if I can quantify something in
dollars and cents, if I can say, hey, you know, I went
out and I did 30 million impressions, and that
corresponds to x amount of ad dollars. And like,
this is how we can quantify this is how we can
just put some value of what I'm doing. That can be
really powerful in the right in the right room, but
so can anecdotes of somebody like, hey, that course
that you made, really made it easier for me to
understand this concept and I signed up or
something.
Yeah, makes a lot of sense. Going back to your
developer relations work at Replit. You are in a
very, very interesting position, at least I find
it very interesting, where now it's largely about
vibe coding, right? If you encounter an engineer or
somebody with a lot of experience in the
industry, they might approach this concept, this
topic as something to dismiss, you know, something
like, oh, vibe coding, ew. But curious, how do you
define and explain what vibe coding to such
skeptical users? And how do you address this kind
of feedback?
Oh, man. Yeah, vibe coding gets a lot of shade. I
think there are a lot of things to unpack here.
So first, I mean, there are a lot of people
that just, they don't even know what the term is.
Maybe they've never used vibe coding before. Like
they're still like, we're definitely living in
bubble NSF, this is something new that's being
adopted. And the skepticism is warranted, right? With
any new technology, I think they're a group of
skeptics and they're a group of early adopters. And
so all I'll say is that in my own experience as a
dev, there's a spectrum, right? There's like
people that vibe code, like I've never written
code before. And there are devs that are super
surgical and tactical and use this tool to just
get more stuff done. The reason I believe in vibe
coding, and the reason I work at Replit is
because a year ago, when Sonic first came out, I
realized, holy cow, I can just get more stuff done.
And for me, you know, it's I appreciate the art
of writing code that's important. But for me, it's
like about what I can build and the stuff that I
can get done and the people that I can help. And
so once I realize I can help more people and I
can get more stuff done, that really convinced me
immediately, I should be using this more. And
again, if you understand how to, or well, not
again, if you understand how to use context and
you understand how to use LLMs as a tool to
accomplish goals, there are really amazing things
that you can do. So if you're a dev, and you've
been saying, hey, you know, like, I don't need
any of this vibe coding nonsense, you know, I'm
a, you know, I'm a hardcore, you know, DevOps guy
or whatever, give it a shot. Try and find the
right tools, spend 30 minutes or an hour
playing around with it, for sure. I think
you'll find it useful if you use it in the
right way. If you're somebody who's saying, I
can't stand all these vibe coders out here
that have never written code, building apps,
you know, I get it. At Replit, our goal is to
empower everyone to create software, regardless
of what background you come from. But I view
things a little bit differently, right? I
think if you think about vibe coding as a
creative tool, I think it's very interesting,
creative tool, a tool for, or productive tool,
tool for entrepreneurs, a tool for
professionals, a tool for people who are
inspired with an idea that just want to
create what they always have. The same way
that you think about maybe a MacBook as a
powerful tool, or you think about, you know,
some of these classical, even like Nike, right?
Nike in 1970. There is no finish line, right?
Like these, you buy the shoes to
accomplish amazing things, right? I think
about Replit as somewhere you can go to
build amazing things, right? And vibe
coding, right? Like, I think people want to
talk about it as like, oh, you go and it
just magically just like apps just appear
like you don't have to do anything. It's
actually just engineering. I don't, you
know, this is maybe a hot take. It's I
can't go to people and just say, I'm gonna
teach you how to be an engineer. But good
vibe coders are good engineers. Like I'm
gonna think logically, they're good
builders. Like if you can fix a motorcycle,
if you can fix a car engine, you're gonna
be an amazing vibe coder. If you know how
to use an Excel spreadsheet, you're gonna
be amazing vibe coder because under the
hood, it's just logic. It's just software
engineering. It's software engineering
without software engineering, right? And
it's first principles thinking, it's
systems thinking, it's breaking down
problems. It's product sense. If you go
into if you open up your phone, and you
use an app, and you're like, this app
sucks because XYZ, XYZ, XYZ. And these
are the things I want to change. You're
gonna be an outstanding vibe coder
because it's being super conscientious
and pedantic and having attention to
detail. And these are characteristics
of a software engineer. But there's the
code is English, right? And so the more
I explore these ideas, the more I try
to communicate to engineers, don't
necessarily think about it as just
like people, I don't know, like
frolicking and just like willy-nilly
creating apps. But think about it as a
tool for accomplishing goals. The
goal is to create something amazing.
And more and more with AI, we can do
that with natural language. It's kind
of hard approach it.
Yeah, no, I think that I think that
makes sense. Because I give a talk
about this at Next.js comp, where
it's like, AI shouldn't replace you as
the developer, but you should be the
developer delegating to it like in
insane detail. And that's why I am a
huge, huge supporter of voice mode,
whether that be via like super
whisper or something like that.
Because I am amazing at like
visualizing out like the flow chart
of how the app works and how the
stuff works. So I will literally my
girlfriend will come in and be like,
what the hell are you doing? Because
she'll see me and I'm just like,
literally like this just like
dictating like at the speed of
light to like the agent and I
submit paragraphs at a time, but
it does it like insanely well,
because it's just I reference all
the little context bits and
everything like that. So we can
actually understand what's
happening. So I think that pairing
of yourself as a developer with
the agent as the tool can just
push you even further and just
make it work seamlessly. So um,
that's, that's spot on, right?
And commonly, that's how I'm using
replet. I'm using I'm doing the
same thing with voice. And I'm
like, looking at this thing, I'm
like a locked in, I'm like,
change this button, make this
thing work different. I want to
implement this other thing,
right? But the thing I want to
you know, the point I think
that's important to make is
that even if you've never used
code before, even if you don't
know what code is, the latency
to information is like zero now,
right? Like you have your
coding agent open and you're
like, what's a shader? I don't
know what a shader is. Explain
to me what a shader is and
explain to me how it works in my
application. And you can just
literally double click on every
piece of information and learn
so fast. So the latency to
information is lower. You know,
we talked about we're developers
talk about developer experience.
What is developer experience?
Well, it's like feedback loops,
cognitive load and flow
state, right? And so all of
these things, we can lower the
feedback loop to information,
but then also implementing the
features, we can lower the
cognitive load of having to
switch to multiple tools by
just asking our chat
interface. And ultimately, that
gets us in a flow state as a
builder, whether you're someone
new to code or your software
engineer, that lets you just
do more stuff and build
amazing things. And Ryan, I
think like what you're
mentioning there is you can
use voice, you can use
super whisper, whisper flow,
shout out to nay to turn
these things take you want to
mind meld with the computer,
right? You just want to be in
this like freakin loop. It's
super fun. But yeah, man, I
think that's spot on for what
like vibe coding really is.
You get you get like in this
flow state. And I was in this
today when I was just debugging
one of the incidents that I
have. And it just it just
feels like, especially if you
use like a fast model like
composer or something like that.
It just feels like you're in
this flow state where you're
just input output input output
and you're generating really
good code because it's all
super, super detail oriented
and everything like that. And
it's just once you experience
it, you're like, Oh, man, I
love that feeling. It kind of
gives me the rush of like
coding itself, but I'm just
able to work 10 times faster.
And it's just it's it's a
crazy, crazy experience.
Here's a here's I like to
flip this. I like to ask
the interviewers questions
sometimes how do you guys
like make sure that you're
writing code because I was
like, I had to write some
Python the other day. I was
like, dude, I'm a little
rusty. You know what I'm
seeing? That's the that's
the thing with me. I don't
really write code. Um, I, I
know the syntax because I
ingest it enough. So, um, if
I've got to like edit
something, I can do it
really, really well with
like cursor tab. But if
you were to plot me down
in the old reflet editor,
like, I don't know what
three years ago, and it's
like, hey, create a react
app type script, I can
kind of do okay. But
create like a react app or
something like that. Dude, I
would be cooked, especially
with all this like react
query stuff and all the
query and the hooks I would
be absolutely just gone,
gone.
Dan, you got any tips?
Yeah, I actually do not
trust models enough to
just ship code the way I
wanted to be shipped. There
are just things that I
didn't manage to capture
because there's like so
many preferences that I've
built over my career. I've
been coding for over a
decade now. And I just
don't trust the agent
outputs to always deliver
on what I want. And I
occasionally like on not
occasionally on every
prompt that I use in
cursor cursor being my
preference ID, I always
have to manually insert
some code. Either, um,
either add some error
handling the way I wanted
or fix how the logging is
done or remove the
ridiculous, super
elaborate comments. You
know, uh, there's always
something I have to change
manually. Uh, but yeah, I
am as, as the time is
moving, I'm trusting the
cursor agent
generations more and
more. That's like a very,
very consistent trend.
Like as the models
improve, I trust these
models more and more.
Yeah, I don't know. Maybe
this is an irrational
fear of mine that I'm
going to be like walking
through a bad part of
San Francisco. Shout out
Daniel Lurie's clean.
He's cleaning things up,
but you know, you're in
a bad part of San
Francisco and some guy
jumps out and he's like,
you need to write some
object, object oriented
Python or it's over,
dude, like you better do
it. And if that, if that
happened today, like I
don't know what would
happen, but, uh, you
know, um, I think, I
think there's something
to it right where it's
like, it depends on the
type of repo you're in.
If you're in like an
established repo with
like patterns, you can
use that as context to
get the AI to write
code the way you want
it to. If you're doing
a greenfield project,
it's going to do its
own thing, which is
okay. Maybe like the
thing I tell her, like
developers that like
people think now, oh,
rep was only for vibe
coders. But if you're a
dev and you want to
prototype something
really quick, it's
actually a great way to
just spin up a full
stack app. And then,
you know, you can just
like build it, rebuild
it the way you want to
after you validate that
it works. We use like a
pretty opinionated
architecture, but it's
still, you know, it's
still AI written code.
And so it might not
do things the way you
want it to. But then
if you're writing, if
you're going from
scratching, you're
starting, maybe you
bootstrap it with like
coding standards and
you're still going to
get like weird
comments and dude, I, I
actually, so I did, I did
this the other day. I
like built something out
with Python and I was
like reading every line.
And I was like, what the
heck is this? It's a
crazy stuff. It was like,
why are you doing string
comprehension that way?
It's like crazy stuff.
Yeah, yeah, it's, uh,
it's, it's interesting
because if there, if I
was able to visualize
like a graph of my AI
usage over like a new
project, um, it, it
definitely goes like
this while I'm like
still establishing the
patterns. And then once
I've established like my
API patterns, I set up
my cursor rules. I've
set up like my type
safety and how I want
that stuff to be. I've
set up like this lent
and build cycle. So that
way, if it makes after
like a plan session, it
runs a lint and then
it runs a build. And
then after that, and
after everything's kind
of finalized, then I
just kind of, it is
just absolute flow
state. Like my, I'm
very, very happy. The
current state of the
inbound, um,
repositories in, I've
got so many cursor
rules and everything
like that. Literally, um,
I've got a workflow
that comes in. So if
someone reports like
there's a little feedback
card inside the app,
someone types in a
feedback thing and
report some technical
issue and an AI flag
to this technical, I
throw it over to a
tempo background agent
and it has no like
special prompt or
anything like that. It
just literally with some
like set up, it throws
in the user's issue
and it normally fixes
it. Like I'd say maybe
9 out of 10 times and
it just throws me a PR
that I'm able to review
and everything's kind of
like auto done. And I
feel like that's going
to be like the next
evolution of the web
where it's like
everybody just has more
automation and
automotive capabilities
to be able to work on
anything. So it's like a
dev rel now become sort
of like a product
manager in a, in a
sense, because he can
kind of overreach and
then like a designer can
actually reach into
some of the code.
So yeah, it's, it's
really interesting. But
yeah, I think,
yeah, sorry. The cool
thing about vibe coding
is they can classify
it as many things. It
can be an engineering
manager instructing a
team of agents being
self engineers. Somebody
doesn't perform just
firearm, right? Or a
product manager
specifying the product
specific writing product
specifications that are
passing it along to an
engineering team,
right? There are so many
ways to do it and
there's no right way
honestly, like it
depends on your flow,
right? I mean, I think
everybody wants to make
things black and white.
And it's just like, it's
not, there's nuance as
it would turn out. It's
not like Twitter, like,
you know, or it feels
post hot takes. But I
really like what Ryan
said, my most successful
like vibe coding
projects repos, I
think I'm most proud of
the replet documentation,
which I've written a
blog post on like kind
of how we did that was
I just wrote a ton of
docs for the docs, you
know, like all the
rules, all the examples,
all of the templates,
all of the bash commands
and PMPM scripts that
an agent could use. I
just built all the
infra for the agent to
do to check its own work
and to like have
context. And then when
you do that, you unlock
background agents, you
unlock like vibe coding
tools. And then you can
set up these workflows
where the scaffolding is
automated, right? And
it sounds like that's
what Ryan's doing. But
hopefully nobody like
prompt injects the issue
submission box from.
Yeah, well, that's
the, that's another fun
thing that's kind of
come about it's AI has
gotten really good at
when you stack it in
layers to notice that
they're like one of those
layers. It is like an
issue. Like for example,
for that feedback loop,
if you're interested,
when that feedback loop
comes in, there's an
agent that essentially does
the evaluation, but
then there's two levels
of agent above it that
essentially say, Hey,
this might be prompt
injection attack, can
you evaluate it? And
then the agent above
that checks, it
basically vibe checks. And
it's, I think it's
using, it's like sonnet
for GPT five. And then
I think like Gemini or
something like that at
the top level. So there's
like overlap with that
as well. So, um, yeah,
it's, it's, it's super,
it's super interesting
because that's now an
attack factor. It's
essentially XSS in, um,
in AI form. So yeah,
yeah, I mean, it's like,
it's more like if you
don't realize like what
an MCP server does and
you like plug in some,
you know, uh, something
with, uh, sensitive
permissions that has
access to data. Some of
those MCPs attacks are
pretty crazy.
Oh yeah. MC I was just
about to bring it in.
Like the, there are
some really, really
scary attacks you can
do with MCP servers
nowadays. Uh,
what was it? There was
the one that was
published where like
somebody like prompted
injected a linear ticket
or it was like some
Jira ticket or
something that like is
something crazy.
Yeah, I think those
types of attacks are
now categorized as
context poisoning. Um,
might be wrong. Anyway,
but yeah, actually you
might want to stay in
touch with Ryan Matt
because Ryan, if
anybody in the world is
probably a very good
authority in vibe
coding, this person,
like when the composer
model came out by
cursor, like in a day,
this person generated
2 billion tokens. I
was like, how is this
even possible? Can you
do that? Have they
sent has open AI
sent you an award yet
Ryan for, uh, I don't
use open AI enough for
that. I've got a, I've
got a cursor tab key. Um,
there you go. But, um,
other than other than
that, I do not have an
open it. Oh wait, hold
on. Uh, do I have it
here? I don't think I
do. I have a custom
thanks to my 3d printing
company. I have a
custom cursor, three
comma club award that I
don't think I have over
here, but it's like a
little plaque that
basically just shows like
three comma club. I
don't know where that
is. Interesting. Well,
but yeah, back to
life coding back to life
coding. Uh, you taught
life coding to a bunch
of people for a while
now, right? Uh, and as
we just have seen, uh,
you have a few opinions
on like how it should
be taught and what the
implications of getting
into it. Uh, curious, uh,
in your experience so
far teaching developers
from various backgrounds.
What are the three
skills people think they
need versus three that
they actually need to
interact with this new
tooling? Well, uh,
because I imagine people
really come in with a
lot of misconceptions
when they get started.
Three skills people
think they need versus
what they actually need.
Yeah. Um, yeah, I
think one, the one I
see most often is like
people think that
there's like a magic
incantation or prompt
since like anybody that
doesn't understand maybe
hasn't spent the time
to like deeply
understand how something
works, thinks that
there's like some
shortcut to it. So it's
like, Oh, what do I
prompt Claude to then
paste into replant? And
I'm like, that's not how
you approach solving
problems, right? Uh, so
like, so then maybe
that's one expectation.
Um, the second
expectation is I just
have a box and I'm going
to type in like
whatever I think and
that it's going to just
magically appear. Maybe
that's similar to the
first one, but, uh,
also not how it works,
right? Like you have
to, can this tool do
what I want it to do?
That's really the
first question that you
should be asking. And
the, the follow up
question to that is,
what do I want to do?
And if you're deeply
asking yourself, what
am I trying to build?
Well, you can go kind
of up the, up the
ladder there to say,
well, then what are the
components that go
into this thing? Now
I get it. Not
everybody thinks that
way. That's like a
very first principles,
like, you know, just
how I think maybe
designers approach the
problem differently. Hey,
I want to create a
beautiful experience for
people and then turn
that into something
real understood. But at
some point you have to
be asking like deeper
questions rather than
just like, um, kind of
shooting in the dark,
right? So maybe three
things. First, it's kind
of like, uh, oh, I need
to know like the
incantation or like the
secret process to how I
do things. Second, it's
like, oh, um, there's
some magical tool that
will solve my problem.
And I just type in a
prompt box that, that,
you know, creates my
idea and I don't have to
do any work. Three,
how do I make a
million dollars five
coding? Okay. Like, I
just, you know, like
that's like the
catchy, you know, Oh,
make me $1 billion. No
mistakes. Okay. I
get it. You know, it's
now we're selling
courses and it's at
mafia stuff or
whatever. Um, I don't
think any of that is, uh,
is super important. Um,
let's talk about like
what I do. Thing is
important. Uh, the
ability to think
logically and break
down problems. Number
one, right? Okay. I
have this thing that I
want to build. Why, why
am I building it? What
does it do? It's in
some senses. It's just
kind of like product
thinking, right? Like,
uh, can I break this
thing down into little
building blocks? And
you know, as an
engineer, you might
call it an architecture
diagram. You might
call it, um, thinking
about the services that
go in your
application. Uh, but
if you're a, uh, uh, if
you're not an engineer,
if you're someone new to
vibe, but you might say,
oh, well, I want to
generate images. How do
I generate images for
my users? Well, you
could ask AI and do
research to understand
what that looks like.
And you probably
learned that there's a
service like maybe
Google nano bananas,
which weren't used.
And then you might
ask, well, how do I
put that in an app? As
it would turn out on
rebel it, uh, soon
that you know, you
won't really need to
ask that question, but
you might learn that
there's a thing called
an API key that you
get, uh, and you have
to use a certain type
of prompt to get an
app to use that thing.
So first I would say,
um, you know, like the
ability to break down
problems and first
principles thinking
second, uh, this is
actually one I've been
thinking about a lot
lately debugging, like
debugging is a skill
that everyone should
just learn for their
life. Period. Like if
you just want to do
stuff, learn debugging.
So, uh, one of our
engineers at replant
Ryan, shout out Ryan
dude is like a
legendary Nick's
contributor. Like if
you just like look up
a Nick's problem, if
you just go into
Google and you're like,
oh, Hey, you know, I
have this problem with
the Nick's package or
there will be like a
form link that you'll
find some Nick's OS
forum. Link and Ryan
will be in there like
answering that question.
Actually insane. Uh,
he was like, Oh, hey
everyone, I'm going to
do a tech talk on this
book called debugging.
And I'm only like, I
haven't read the entire
book. I'm working my
way through it. But
what I realized is
everyone should just
know how to debug to
solve problems. It's
like, Hey, if I want
to go, I mentioned,
you know, earlier in
the talk, if I want
to fix something on my
truck, if I want to
fix something in my car,
if I want to fix a
piece of electronics or
a lamp, I have to
understand the problem,
understand the domain
that I'm working in,
like the scope of the
thing. Why isn't this
light turning on? Well,
is it plugged in? Um,
well, does the light
bulb work? Well, uh, if
the it's plugged in and
the light bulb works,
there's something
wrong between the
socket and the light
bulb. And so now I can
start drilling down into
that problem. And if
you understand debugging
principles, which are
like, you know, Oh,
I have an app and
it's broken. Well, my
app has a front end,
the things I see, and
it has back end things
I don't see. How can I
understand what's going
on in those things to
deep, to, to figure out
what the root cause of
the issue is? This is a
skill that I don't see a
lot of non-technical
people have. Even some
engineers could be
better at this. I
could be better at it.
Right. Um, and
sometimes I forget
when I have a problem.
Oh, Hey, like maybe my
camera's not working. I,
you know, what if I
joined the screen, my
camera wasn't working.
Sometimes I'll just
be like, I'll just
turn it off on again.
I'm going to be
lazy. No, sit down,
read the docs, read
the instruction manual,
understand what you're
working with, and
then try to solve the
problem. And that's
debugging. I think
everybody should just
learn how to do that. Um,
so yeah, I'll take a
pause there because I,
you know, this is all,
this is all a line up.
Yeah, that was good.
That was good. I just
wish we had more time
to let you, uh, to
keep talking about this.
Yeah. It's actually
interesting. Debugging
as a critical skill to
have, I, I super
resonated with that. Uh,
I, I don't know. I
mean, you'd already
know this, but rubber
duct debugging. There's
a reason why I
purchased to every
single person I
need. Uh, it's an
incredible skill to have.
It's essentially, I
don't know if you're
familiar with the
concept of Socratic
dialogue, but that's
what it is. You're
engaging yourself in the
conversation that helps
you identify the problem
and solve it during the
dialogue. Right. Uh,
and Robert, that being,
you know, an
inanimate object that
you're talking to just
helps your mind
facilitate this process.
That's all. Um, but
yeah, uh, actually I
recommend this to
everybody to try, uh,
engaging with your, uh,
LLMs in a Socratic
dialogue and see if
that improves your, uh,
process of learning or
solving problems. It's
spreading incredible
stuff. I wrote that
down. I'm going to, I'm
going to, I'm going to
think through that one a
little bit more deeply.
Do we have time for me
to give one more thing?
Yes. Okay, cool. Um,
because I was like,
kind of trying to
assemble my thoughts to
remember, I think the
biggest thing, biggest
thing I see from
people is a fear of
failure. And just for
people that get are
getting into engineering,
these are people who
are coming to vibe
coding. You know, we're
used to products where,
you know, like you open
up, I don't know, you
open up Duolingo and you
press the button and
you learn Spanish. It
works. You know, maybe
you fail in that
process, but the app
works and then they
come into building and
the app doesn't work.
Like you try to build
something and just
breaks. This is like
when I was learning to
be an engineer, I was
like trying to write a
hello world program or
like install Postgres
on my laptop and, you
know, I don't know,
2018 or something. And
it took me like a day
to figure out. And
like, that's
demoralizing me. You
want to feel like a
loser. You sit down to
open up a textbook and
you're on page one at
the end of the day, you
know, it's like, okay,
what I think most
people don't understand
is that like to do
anything interesting,
you just have to
repeatedly fail over
and over and over
again. And, you know,
like vibe coding tools
are getting so good. In
some ways, you can
circumvent a lot of
that failure. And a lot
of our successes as a
society are built on
the failure of other
people, right? Like, I
hope no one ever ever
has to open a
textbook to learn
Python again, the way
that I did. You should
chat with an LLM if you
want to learn Python.
Maybe one day you don't
need to, I don't know.
But the being an
excellent engineer,
being a professional
means just failing
repeatedly over and
over and over again. And
so in some sense, like I
want to help people vibe
code and build amazing
things. I want that to
be as easy as possible.
But you will bump into
a place where you fail
and you're stuck and
you don't know what to
do. And the number one
skill is going to be
like persevering and
finding the internal
motivation to say, I'm
an engineer, I'm trying
to build this thing and
I want to be a staff
engineer. Maybe that's
you. I want to be a
manager. I want to lead
a team. I want to be an
entrepreneur. I want to
start a business. I want
to, you know, help my
family. I want to like
the type of person
that I've always wanted
to be. I'm just going to
fail over and over and
over again. And I'm not
going to let that stop
me.
Yeah, that's actually
an excellent. Yeah,
sorry. It's an
excellent piece of
device that actually
extends well beyond
engineering also, right?
Like, in general,
tolerance to failure is
something that will get
you very, very far if you
keep increasing it. And
that's how you grow. You
fail. You just keep
failing continuously
until you become the
best at the thing. Right.
Fully great. And I
mean, it's it's public
speaking. It's coming on
podcasts like this. I've
done podcasts. I look
like the biggest idiot
in the world. I mean,
I probably still do. You
know what? We got a
couple hundred people
watching. You know, it
is what it is. So, you
know, I think part of
it is having a healthy
respect, disregard for
what other people think
of you and your
mistakes. And again,
like you ship
something that has a
mistake in it. It's very
easy to get self
conscious about that as
a dev rel, right? We
talked about getting into
dev rel. Oh, I'm going to
put myself on camera and
I'm going to get in
front of the internet,
everybody, my family,
like all these people.
What if I do something
dumb? What if people
think I'm a loser? What
if people don't like my
work? It's okay. Promise,
I promise no one cares.
I promise no one cares
at all. But eventually
through that persistence,
you get good at what
you do. And it's just,
you know, that's part
of it, right? Yeah.
Cool. So we are almost
at the top of the hour.
So we're going to start
working on our wrap up.
Where should folks
follow your work and
start building and
learn how to vibe code
with the replica and
everything like that?
That this is your one
to two minutes of self
plug and replica plug.
That's ending. Yeah,
you can follow along
with me on on X. I'm
on LinkedIn. I have a
YouTube channel. I also
do a lot of content for
replet socials. But you
know, on X, it's Mattie
peak recent recent handle
acquisition on LinkedIn.
It's my name. Same thing
on YouTube. Or you can
just go at replet on X
LinkedIn YouTube. And
that's where I create
content. Through there,
I try to share everything
that I build. I try to
really build in public
and you know, we're
doing it live now, but
I'm hoping in the next
couple of weeks, we'll
have some first party
replet materials to
learn everything you need
to know from what AI is
to what vibe coding is.
So that's kind of coming
soon. You'll be able to
find that on all the
channels I mentioned
earlier. Awesome. And
we're going to close out
with the usual classic
next step question. If
you could go 10 years
into the past and talk
to yourself will be one
piece for the vibes you
would share.
Okay, go 10 years into
the past and talk to
myself. Alright, so like
we have to frame this
as it what year is it?
It's 2025. What was I
doing in 2015? Yeah,
I'm gonna date myself
here in 2015. I was a
freshman in college. And
I was just a total idiot.
And you know, I was like
doing things that a
freshman in college very
much did. At the time,
you know, I was playing
baseball in school, I was
studying physics,
economic, like I was I
went to liberal arts
school. So it's just like
doing everything. I think
I would have pushed
myself to practice a lot
of the things that I
just kind of preach to
you all, which is like
not be afraid, afraid of
failing, and to think
more critically about
what I want to do and
less about what other
people want me to do. And
I think as a freshman
college, I was very
immature in that way that
I cared a lot about what
other people thought of
me. And it wasn't until
later in my life that I
started acting in a way
that aligned more with
what I cared and what I
wanted. And so when you
see all of these things,
if you follow me on
Twitter, you'll see I
post a lot about
fitness, post a lot about
replet, I post a lot about
doing things outside and
the things that I care
about and the things
that I think these are
genuinely uniquely who
I am and the work that
I do is a byproduct of
who I am as a person. And
I wish I would have went
back and I told my, you
know, self in 2015, that
is a lot more important
than what other people
think of you. What's
that? There's that that
quote, that Tolstov, you
know, you've forsaken
yourself for nothing or
whatever. Yeah. That's
right. So what is the
actual quote? You have
forsaken. I don't know.
We're not gonna find
a war. Sin is that
you've destroyed and
betrayed yourself for
nothing. 100% man, that's
that's what I would have
won back and just said
that. Excellent. That's
excellent advice. And
yeah, TLDR, don't let
anybody tell you who you
are. Do what you think is
right for yourself.
Right. Only you know who
you are and what you
care about. Awesome. I
think that's a good
place to wrap up. Thank
everybody for tuning in.
Thank you so much, Matt
for joining us. I
think that was an
excellent episode. And
we've got a lot of
useful advice out there
for folk. But yeah, and
thank you everybody in
the audience for joining.
Keep an eye out. We'll
be doing a lot more of
those next step live
streams moving
forward. So yeah, thanks
everybody for tuning in.
Awesome. Yeah, thank you
Matt. And we will catch
you all later. We will
see you later.